https://www.backwoodshome.com/contact-us/privacy-policy/

your password
Forgot your password?
your email
A password will be e-mailed to you.
Backwoods Home Magazine
This document was last updated on August 16, 2020.
ACKNOWLEDGMENT AND ACCEPTANCE OF TERMS
Self-Reliance Publications LLC is committed to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Statement sets forth our current privacy practices with regard to the information we collect when you or your computer interact with our website. By accessing www.backwoodshome.com, whether directly or through alternate web addresses, links from other websites, advertising banners, or any other means, you acknowledge and fully understand Self-Reliance Publications LLC’s Privacy Statement and freely consent to the information collection and use practices described in this Website Privacy Statement.
MAILING LISTS
Self-Reliance Publications LLC respects the privacy of its subscribers, customers and readers. We never have, and never will, sell, rent, loan, give away, or otherwise share the name and address of anyone who does business with us or communicates with us, by whatever means, if they have requested we not do so.
When you do business with us, we ask that you tell us if you do not want your name and mailing address included on our list of people who would like to receive information from other companies with products or services of interest to self-reliant people.
Regardless of your choice, we will NEVER provide your name to any business that promotes hate, bigotry, pornography or the like.
If you tell us you do not want to be part of the mailing list, we will permanently flag your account so that it will not be used when compiling mailing lists. If you change your mind, you must contact us and request future inclusion on the list.
If you are included on our mailing list, you may request removal at any time. All requests for inclusion, removal or other matters relating to the Special Offers list should be emailed to customer-service@backwoodshome.com.
You may also send your request via U.S. Mail to: Customer Service, Backwoods Home Magazine, P.O. Box 308, Philomath, OR 97370.
COMMUNICATING WITH US
When you communicate with us by sending comments about the magazine, web site, articles, or other issues, we may include your letter in the “Letters” section of the magazine or in the “Feedback” page on the web site, or both. If we use your letter or comment we may include your name, city or town, state or province, and country (if not USA).
If you do not want your letter published, or if you do not want your name, city or town, state or province, or country published, we ask that you tell us each time you write, preferably at the beginning of the communication.
Editorial comments may be sent via email to editor@backwoodshome.com
Comments and questions about the website may be sent via email to webmaster@backwoodshome.com.
PARTICIPATING MERCHANT POLICIES
Related services and offerings with links from this website, including vendor sites, have their own privacy statements that can be viewed by clicking on the corresponding links within each respective website. Online merchants and others who participate in Self-Reliance Publications LLC services are encouraged to participate in industry privacy initiatives and to take a responsible attitude towards consumer privacy. However, since we do not have direct control over the policies or practices of participating merchants and other third parties, we are not responsible for the privacy practices or contents of those sites. We recommend and encourage that you always review the privacy policies of merchants and other third parties before you provide any personal information or complete any transaction with such parties.
INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND HOW WE USE IT
Self-Reliance Publications LLC collects certain information from and about its users three ways: directly from our Web Server logs, the user, and with Cookies.
Web Server Logs
When you visit our Website, we may track information to administer the site and analyze its usage. Examples of information we may track include:
Your Internet protocol address.
The kind of browser or computer you use.
Number of links you click within the site.
State or country from which you accessed the site.
Date and time of your visit.
Name of your Internet service provider.
Web page you linked to our site from.
Pages you viewed on the site.
Personal Information From Users
Visitors to our website purchase goods and services. When you register and/or check out, we will request some personal information such as name, address, email, telephone number or facsimile number, account number and other relevant information. If you are purchasing goods or a service, we will request financial information. Any financial information we collect is used only to bill you for the goods and/or services you purchased. If you purchase by credit card, this information may be forwarded to your credit card provider.
For other types of registrations, such as for our Readers’ Forum, we will ask for the relevant information.
You may also be asked to disclose personal information to us so that we can provide assistance and information to you. For example, such data may be warranted in order to provide online technical support and troubleshooting.
We will not disclose personally identifiable information we collect from you to third parties if you ask us not to except to the extent necessary:
To fulfill your requests for goods or services, or
To protect ourselves from liability, or
To respond to legal process or comply with law, or
In connection with a merger, acquisition, or liquidation of the company.
Use of Cookies
Self-Reliance Publications LLC may use cookies to personalize or enhance your user experience. A cookie is a small text file that is placed on your computer or mobile device by a Web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you.
One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. For example, if you personalize a web page, or navigate within the site, a cookie helps the site to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. Hence, this simplifies the process of delivering relevant content and eases site navigation by providing and saving your preferences and login information as well as providing personalized functionality.
Self-Reliance Publications LLC reserves the right to share aggregated site statistics with partner companies, but does not allow other companies to place cookies on our website unless there is a temporary, overriding customer value, such as merging into www.backwoodshome.com a site that relies on third-party cookies or serving third-party advertising.
You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies. If you reject cookies by changing your browser settings then be aware that this may disable some of the functionality on our Website. You also have the ability to delete cookies at any time. Refer to your web browser’s documentation for details.
THIRD-PARTY ADVERTISING
SELF-RELIANCE PUBLICATIONS LLC USES THIRD-PARTY ADVERTISING COMPANIES TO SERVE ADS WHEN YOU VISIT OUR WEBSITE. THESE COMPANIES MAY USE INFORMATION (NOT INCLUDING YOUR NAME, ADDRESS, EMAIL ADDRESS, OR TELEPHONE NUMBER) ABOUT YOUR VISITS TO THIS AND OTHER WEBSITES IN ORDER TO PROVIDE ADVERTISEMENTS ABOUT GOODS AND SERVICES OF INTEREST TO YOU.
GOOGLE AND DOUBLECLICK
GOOGLE, AS A THIRD PARTY VENDOR, USES COOKIES TO SERVE ADS ON OUR SITE(S).
GOOGLE’S USE OF THE DOUBLECLICK DART COOKIE ENABLES IT TO SERVE ADS TO OUR USERS BASED ON THEIR VISIT TO OUR SITE(S) AND OTHER SITES ON THE INTERNET. THE DOUBLECLICK DART COOKIE IS USED BY GOOGLE IN THE ADS SERVED ON PUBLISHER WEBSITES DISPLAYING ADSENSE FOR CONTENT ADS. WHEN USERS VISIT AN ADSENSE PUBLISHER’S WEBSITE AND EITHER VIEW OR CLICK ON AN AD, A COOKIE MAY BE DROPPED ON THAT END USER’S BROWSER. THE DATA GATHERED FROM THESE COOKIES WILL BE USED TO HELP GOOGLE BETTER SERVE ADS OF INTEREST TO VISITORS AND ADSENSE PUBLISHERS BETTER SERVE AND MANAGE THE ADS ON THEIR SITE(S) AND ACROSS THE WEB.
USERS MAY OPT OUT OF THE USE OF THE DART COOKIE BY VISITING THE GOOGLE AD AND CONTENT NETWORK PRIVACY POLICY PAGE.
USE OF TRACKING CODE, WEB BEACONS OR GIF FILES
Backwoods Home Magazine’s Web pages may contain tracking code or electronic images known as Web beacons – sometimes also called single-pixel gifs – that allow Self-Reliance Publications LLC to count users who have visited those pages and to deliver co-branded services. Self-Reliance Publications LLC may include tracking code or Web beacons in promotional e-mail messages or newsletters in order to determine whether messages have been opened and acted upon.
Some of these tracking codes and/or Web beacons may be placed by third party service providers to help determine the effectiveness of our advertising campaigns or email communications. These tracking codes and/or Web beacons may be used by these service providers to place a persistent cookie on your computer. This allows the service provider to recognize your computer each time you visit certain pages or emails and compile anonymous information in relation to those page views, which in turn enables us and our service providers to learn which advertisements and emails bring you to our website and how you use the site. Self-Reliance Publications LLC prohibits tracking codes and Web beacons from being used to collect or access your personal information.
CHANGES TO THIS STATEMENT
Self-Reliance Publications LLC has the discretion to occasionally update this privacy statement. When we do, we will also revise the “updated” date at the top of this Privacy page. We encourage you to periodically review this privacy statement to stay informed about how we are helping to protect the personal information we collect. Your continued use of the service constitutes your agreement to this privacy statement and any updates.
CONTACTING US
If you have questions regarding our Privacy Statement, its implementation, failure to adhere to this Privacy Statement and/or our general practices, please contact customer-service@backwoodshome.com or send your comments to:
Mailing Address:
Backwoods Home Magazine
P.O. Box 308
Philomath, OR 97370
Office Address:
Backwoods Home Magazine
935 NW Circle Blvd, Corvallis, OR 97330
Telephone ” 1-541-250-5134
Office Hours: Monday – Friday, 7 AM to 5 PM Pacific Time
Self-Reliance Publications LLC will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly respond and resolve any problem or question.
Animals
Keeping homestead animals healthy
By Jackie Clay-Atkinson
Issue #169 • January/February, 2018
As a veterinary field technician for more than 20 years, I saw firsthand the frustration and heartbreak when...
Khaki Campbell ducks — The other egg layer
By Amanda J. Kemp
Issue #126 • November/December, 2010
Spring brings the pitter-patter of little feet in the mud, games of tag, and raucous quacks. While...
Good-bye old friend
Broody biddies make sense on the homestead
Brooder in a box
Finding, buying, milking, and living with the family milk cow
Self-Reliance
Starting a Roadside Farm Stand
Homestead water
Moving on: A small town can be a haven during a depression
Stashing Junk Silver for Bad Times
Farm and Garden
How to become a backyard beekeeper
By Sheri Jones
If you’ve been intrigued by the idea of becoming a beekeeper but think you don’t have the space, resources, or knowledge, you’re about to be pleasantly surprised. Backyard beekeeping is a lot...
Read more
Graft Your Own Designer Fruit Trees
By Jackie Clay
Issue #121 • January/February, 2010
Although I've been homesteading for more than forty years, there's always something new to learn. (I figure that if I don't learn at least one thing every day,...
Read more
ABOUT USPhone: 541-250-5134Contact us: customer-service@backwoodshome.comFOLLOW US
Copyright © 2019 Self-Reliance Publications LLC. All rights reserved.
